<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Mazen's Blog</title>
<description>Mazen's RSS feed.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="http://mazzensaadd.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<!-- LB -->

<item>
<title>Virm</title>
<guid>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/blog/virm.html</guid>
<link>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/blog/virm.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 02:29:44 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>
I am a CLI guy myself. Graphical user interfaces don't appeal to me that much. I always go for the terminal-based options instead of the GUI ones. For instance, I am now writing this blog post in vi while listening to Umm Kulthum through a cmus (a terminal-based music player as well).
The terminal-based options are just faster and more efficient for me. 
</p>

<p>
When it comes to navigating the system and manipulating files and directories, I find myself using console file managers like nnn and ranger. But lately, I started relying on pure shell commands, cd and ls for instance. The only thing I missed about tui file managers was the bulk-rename and bulk-remove features. I started looking for alternatives for such features and I found <a href="https://github.com/thameera/vimv">vimv</a>. It lets you bulk-rename files using vim which is great because what I usually do when it comes to renaming is renaming episodes into more convenient names and vim helps get this job done very efficiently using macros.
</p>

<p>
The only thing that was missing is the Bulk-remove feature. So, I created <a href="https://github.com/mazzensaadd/virm">Virm</a>. It lets me use some vim magic and delete multiple files as if they were lines in text files. For me, this is much easier than following specific application's conventions every time I want to do a task. I know how to use vim, so let's use it everywhere xD.
</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Why 12-hour clock is stupid</title>
<guid>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/blog/why-12hour-clock-is-stupid.html</guid>
<link>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/blog/why-12hour-clock-is-stupid.html</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:57:34 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>
        One thing that I don't really understand about the world is how people can make it unnecessarily complicated. It seems like us human beings tend to make things harder for ourselves <em>cuz we can</em>. 
</p>
<p>
        Take the 12-hour clock system people use nowadays as an example. Why would any sufficiently working brain decide on dividing the 24 hours in the day into two 12s? By doing so, you are just adding more ambiguity to your lives. Now, people have to deal with A.M. and P.M. that they don't even know their meanings. Why would anyone assign a specific region of his brain to handle such stupid things? This is completely inefficient. Instead of doing this shit, just be a normal creature and divide your day into equal 24 parts and assign every one of them a number. Not only this will make it easier for kids and even adults to understand, but also it will solve the weird misunderstandings that arise from A.M. and P.M. conflicts.
</p>
<p>
        I myself have always had a problem with the clock system since I was a kid. It was hard to remember what is what when it comes to A.M. and P.M. and I have always thought that this is only adding a complicity layer on something that was supposed to be simple. I'd ask adults around me if A.M. meant night or day and, for some reason, I was never able to remember the difference after a while.
</p>
<p>
        The irony about the whole thing is that only a few portion people actually know what does A.M. and P.M. stand for. They both stand for the Latin words <em>"ante merīdiem"</em> and <em>"post merīdiem"</em> which I doubt that if I showed these words to anyone who uses the 12-hour format, he will be able to recognize it. 
</p>
<p>
        I am using the 24-hour everywhere. My laptop, my phone, my watch, even this website is using the 24-hour system as a clock system. It's easier for me and helps preserve my brain computing power to be used in something more significant.
</p>
<p>
        Please help the world become a better place and start using 24-hour clock. Peace out!
</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>init</title>
<guid>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/blog/init.html</guid>
<link>https://mazzensaadd.github.io/blog/init.html</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 21:29:34 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
    <p>Hi Anon!<br>blog has been initialized...<br>Remember... all I'm offering is the truth. Nothing more. Welcome to the real world.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>

